<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nathaniel</title>
    <link>http://www.nvo.one/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nathaniel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 11:32:20 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.nvo.one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform to build AWS network infrastructure and deploy resources</title>
      <link>http://www.nvo.one/posts/004-automate-iac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 11:32:20 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.nvo.one/posts/004-automate-iac/</guid>
      <description>1. Source Code https://github.com/nhatvo1502/Automate-IaC/tree/main 2. What the code does 2.1. create-resource.yml configure aws credential verify aws credential verify aws s3 permission create s3 bucket for terraform backend copy file from GH to runner verify terraform file terraform init -&amp;gt; apply 2.2 destroy-resource.yml configure aws credential copy file from GH to runner verify terraform file terraform init -&amp;gt; destroy empty s3 backend bucket delete-bucket 2.3 main.tf configure s3 as backend create an s3 bucket create a keypair using a public key from GitHub Secret AMI lookup create VPC create a subnet create a network interface create EC2 instance 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Phishing and Malicious Emails in 2024</title>
      <link>http://www.nvo.one/posts/003-phishing-email/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 09:26:03 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.nvo.one/posts/003-phishing-email/</guid>
      <description>1. Verify sender&amp;rsquo;s email address The sender&amp;rsquo;s origin contains 2 parts: The display name and email@domain.com.
Nhat Vo &amp;lt;nhat.vo@awakenservices.net&amp;gt; Display name: Nhat Vo Email address: nhat.vo@awakenservices.net The display name can be forged while email address cannot.
This is an example of phishing emails: Nhat Vo &amp;lt;nhat.vo@123456.com&amp;gt; Display name: Nhat Vo Email address: nhat.vo@12345.com 2. Don&amp;rsquo;t Trust Unsolicited Emails Be cautious of unexpected emails, especially those requesting personal information or urging you to click on links.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Github Action to generate AWS Credential Report</title>
      <link>http://www.nvo.one/posts/002-aws-credential-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:10:29 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.nvo.one/posts/002-aws-credential-report/</guid>
      <description>I. Introduction This project is inspired by one of my dear friends. Instead of using the AWS Console to generate a credential report, we would set up a runner on GitHub Actions to automate this task. It&amp;rsquo;s a very cool experiment, and I hope that by the end, I can apply and scale this concept into a part of a bigger project down the road.
II. Our Game-plan We will leverage Github Action to execute a set of commands to generate AWS Credential Report, download it, decode, pipe the content into csv file and finally copy to a existing S3 bucket.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://www.nvo.one/posts/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 16:40:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.nvo.one/posts/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Nhat Vo. I&amp;rsquo;m an IT Officer and off-seasoned Software Dev with a keen interest in cloud technology (especially AWS). This blog will be my jounal where I would write about my personal cloud projects and anything IT related.
When I&amp;rsquo;m away from the keyboard, I like to tinker with my car and travel with my favorite people.
Thank you for visiting
NV</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
